“嗨，货鼓郎”
# Hey, Mister Tambourine Man #
“为我演奏一曲”
# Play a song for me #
- “在这铿锵的早晨” - B
- # In the jingle-jangle morning... # - "B."
- “让我与你同去” - A
- # I'll come following... # - "A."
玩得开心吗？亲爱的
Man: You having fun, sweetheart?
是的
Girl: Yes.
啊
Ahh.
宝贝，我希望你做得比我好
Well, I hope you're doing better than me, baby.
- 你做的是什么？ - 为妈妈做的项链
- What are you making? - A necklace for Mom.
是吗？让我看看
Yeah? Let me see.
哇，又一条？
Wow. Another one?
- 是呀 - 亲爱的？
- Yes. - Woman: Honey?
今天有两条了？
That's two today.
- 是呀 - 哦
- Yeah. - Yeah.
亲爱的？
Honey?
- 在 - 帮我开一下门吧？
- Yeah? - Waiting for the help to get that?
我觉得你和我都是帮手
I thought you and I were the help.
- 洗手吃饭去，小南瓜 - 好
- Go wash up for dinner, pumpkin. - Okay.
嗯，闻起来很香 可以外卖吗？
Mmm, smells nice. That takeout?
妈妈，看…
Mommy, look at-
不！
No!
不！啊！
No! Ahh!
哦！别，别，别
Oh! No no no!
你没法跟天斗
You can't fight fate.
我们得离开这鬼地方了 快走吧！
Man: We gotta get the fuck out of here. Come on!
哦，不，不
Oh! Oh no!
不！
Thug: No!
- 你他妈在干什么？ - 不！
- What the fuck are you doing? - No!
妈的停下！ 我们快走！
Fucking stop! Let's go!
他妈给我闭嘴！
Just shut the fuck up!
不！
No!
棒极了
It's cool.
小孩喜欢我
Kids like me.
不，希瑟
No! Heather!
不，不！
No no!
《守法公民》
- 尼克 - 布雷，怎么了？
- Nick. - Bray, what's happenin'?
威利斯是我一起划艇的朋友 他小孩的案子怎么样了？
Willis is a rowing buddy of mine. Where are we on his kid's case?
- 威利斯？ - 是啊
- Willis? - Yeah.
- 哦，我把他踢到少管所去了 - 为什么那样做？
- Oh, I kicked it down to juvie. - Why did you do that?
因为这案子很没劲 当他承认谋杀时
'Cause the case was a dog. The kid was only 15 years old
这个孩子才只有15岁
when he committed the murder.
你舍得影响你那百分之九十五的定罪率记录么
You wouldn't want to jeopardize your 95% conviction rate.
- 其实是百分之九十六 - 现在九十六了？
- It's actually 96%. - 96% now?
是的，你得好好记记账本了
Yes. You gotta keep your books better than that.
你知道，如果我没理解错的话 我会说你想取代我的职位
You know, if I didn't know any better, I'd say you were gunning for my job.
你确实说的对
You do know better.
而你也该知道我的目标要更高
And you know that I'm aiming much higher than that.
他们请求撤回此案
Woman: They filed a motion to dismiss,
但艾布拉姆法官坚持不同意
but there's no way that Judge Abrams honors it.
我想我们可以搬出RICO法令 （反犯罪组织侵蚀合法组织法）
I think that we can get him on RICO.
莎拉,这阵子你就只做了这些?
All that time and that's what you come back with, Sarah?
你也许应该重新评估下自己的能力
You might want to reevaluate your research skills.
- 还有其它信息么? - 她说得对
- What else have we got? - Nick: She's right.
什么意思？
Mr. Rice?
RICO是设计处理这类事情的
RICO's designed for this kind of thing.
查一下《有组织犯罪控制法》901章
Check out section 901 of the Organized Crime Control Act.
你就会让莎拉处理这个案子
And you should let Sarah try this case too.
瑞斯先生，我记得以前 这屋子是我说的算
Mr. Rice, last I checked, I was running this room.
她已经做了案件调查的工作 我会监督这个
She's already done the leg-work. I'll oversee it.
我的意思是海伦・凯勒可以试试这个案子 （海伦・凯勒：上世纪美国杰出女性）
I mean, Helen Keller could try this case.
好吧，青年才俊 她搞砸了，就算在你头上
Okay, Boy Wonder, she fucks up, it's on you.
坎特雷尔想见你
Cantrell wants to see you.
好的，我马上就去
All right, I'll be right there.
不，尼克 他想见尼克
No, Nick. He wants to see Nick.
你仍在折磨布林汉姆？
You still torturing Bringham?
这么说吧，我不像他那么看重哈佛学位
Nick: Let's just say I'm less impressed with his Harvard degree than he is.
呵，我们不能都去上福德汉姆
Well, we can't all have gone to Fordham.
我上过福德汉姆夜校
I went to Fordham night school.
知道我在福德汉姆夜校学到什么了吗？
You know what I learned in Fordham night school?
法学院里学不到什么法律
Law school's got nothing to do with law.
我猜你逃了职场哲学的课
Guess you skipped the course on inter-office politics.
我所需要的就是陪审团喜欢我 这不是你教我的吗，乔纳斯？
All I need is a jury to like me. Isn't that what you told me, Jonas?
谢尔顿案件… 进展到哪了？
The Shelton case- where are we?
昨晚出了点差错，伯奇法官那边
It went sideways last night- Judge Burch.
啊…
Ahh.
坏消息，现在怎样办？
Bad news. What now?
- 作笔交易吧 - 尼克，他们杀了小女孩
- Let's make the deal. - They killed a little girl, Nick.
- 这是一个不完美的体制 - 而我们是不完美公仆
- It's an imperfect system. - And we its imperfect servants.
- 不过，你还是可以赢下这个案子 - 不，不能去冒险
- However you could win this case. - No, can't take that chance.
有一些公正总比没有公正好
Some justice is better than no justice at all.
那你得去告诉那位丈夫
You need to tell the husband.
好的 那是我的工作
Okay. That's part of my job.
很好，因为他正在等着你，现在！
Good, because he's waiting for you right now.
什么？
What?
- 你怎么样？ - 还好，你怎么样？
- How are you doing? - Good. How are you doing?
还好 坐吧，坐吧
Good. Sit. Sit.
呃，一直没有你的消息
Well, I didn't hear back from you
所以我写了一些东西关于这案子
and made some notes on the case.
我有些好主意
I had some good ideas.
好，让我来看看
Yeah, let me take a look at it.
恩，它们只是…
Well, they're just-
我正打算跟你谈这个
I was gonna talk to you about those.
你信任我么？
Do you trust me?
你信任我么，克莱德？
Do you trust me, Clyde?
是的，当然
Yeah, of course.
多比同意作证检举阿米
Darby has agreed to testify against Ames.
有了多比的证词
With Darby's testimony,
阿米就会被判死刑
Ames will go to death row.
嗯，那…多比会怎样？
Um, what about- what about Darby then?
多比将被定罪谋杀
Darby will plead guilty to murder.
- 几级？ - 三级
- In what degree? - Third.
他会服刑多久？五年？
He serves, what? Five years...
最多？
at best?
很抱歉，我不明白
I don't understand. I'm sorry.
我们遇到了麻烦 法官裁定DNA证据不被采用
We had a setback. The judge ruled that the DNA was inadmissible.
- 什么？ - 非法证据排除原则
- What? - Exclusionary rule.
辩方律师的伎俩
The opposing counsel maneuvered it.
你说过这个部分容易辨认
You said this part of the case was clear-cut.
我们在他的衬衫上发现了血迹
We had the blood on his shirt-
这也涵盖在同样的原则下
It's covered under the same rule.
那法医的其它证据呢？
What about the rest of the forensic evidence?
那些都不是决定性的，克莱德
It's not conclusive, Clyde.
好吧，没关系 我看见…我看见他们的脸了
Okay, that's okay. 'Cause I saw- I saw their faces.
我亲眼看到他们行凶 他们杀了我的小女儿，尼克
I saw them do it. I mean, he killed my little girl, Nick.
克莱德，你晕过去了 你的证词无法令人信服
You blacked out, Clyde. Your testimony won't be reliable.
你站上证人席时 辩方律师会把你撕碎的
You get on the stand and the defense will tear you apart.
不，不，陪审团会相信我的
No no, the jury's gonna believe me though.
- 因为这就是真相，我们可以… - 我们会输的
- Because it's the truth! We can- - We can lose.
然后我们会一无所获
And then we'd have nothing.
你会浪费一整年的时间 花费百万美元
You will waste a whole year, spend millions of dollars,
然后他俩双双逍遥法外
and then both of them could end up going free.
尼克，他们都有罪 尤其是多比！
Nick, both of them are guilty, especially Darby!
- 你知道这些 - 这与你知道什么无关，克莱德
- You know that. - It's not what you know, Clyde.
而是你能在法庭上证明什么
It's what you can prove in court.
请别与这人做这个交易
Please don't make a deal with this man.
请别与这人交易，他是禽兽
Please don't make a deal with this man. He's a monster-
对不起，协议已经达成了，对不起
I'm sorry, the deal is done. I'm sorry.
我达成了协议
I made the deal.
什么？你怎么可以那样做？
What? How could you do that?
这就是司法体系运作的方式
This is just how the justice system works.
听着，我知道你现在不认可这点
Listen, I know you don't think it right now,
但这其实是我们的胜利
but this is a victory for us.
你们办公室已经认可这个协议了吗？
Woman: Your office has certified this agreement?
是的，法官阁下
Yes, Your Honor.
雷诺斯先生，今天有无高见与法庭分享？
Mr. Reynolds, any great insights to share with the court today?
我是辩方律师，法官阁下 我没多少高见
I'm a defense attorney, Your Honor. I don't have many of those.
没有，法官大人，没有意见了
No, Your Honor. No insights.
很好，那我相信我们可以毫无阻碍地
Good, then I trust that we can move forward with Mr. Ames's trial
推进阿米先生的判决了 审批日期将近了
unimpeded by continuances. A triaI date is imminent.
喂？
Yeah?
瑞斯先生，我的法庭不允许讲手机
There's no cell phones in my courtroom, Mr. Rice.
- 我们说过了… - 抱歉
- We've been over this- - I'm sorry.
一遍地，又一遍地
- and over this, over this...
是的，我有些急事…
Yeah, I had some exigent business I-
下次我就要没收了
Next time it's mine.
- 啊，你结婚了吗？ - 你说什么？
- Ah, you married? - Excuse me?
你结婚了？
Are you married?
请继续喷 这样我就能毁了你
Please fuck this up so I can destroy you.
我不想害人
I wish ill for no man,
不过阿米罪有应得
but Ames deserves to suffer for what he did.
我是说，你没法跟天斗的对吧？
I mean, you can't fight fate, right?
尼克
Nick.
一旦你做了决定 就要学会接受…继续往前
Cantrell: Once you make a decision, live with it- move on.
这份工作，最大的资产就是短暂记忆
This job, your best asset's a short memory.
别自责了，其他很多人都这样干了
Don't beat yourself up. Too many other people out there doing that already.
看，现在那边就有一些人
Look, there's some of them right now.
是不是到了时间你要给我讲些寓言
Isn't this where you tell me some type of old fable
或者启蒙故事的了
or wives' tale-
好了，好了，我想到一个了
All right, all right, I got one.
当马可・奥勒留走过罗马时代广场时
Marcus Aurelius hired a servant to walk behind him
他雇了一个仆人跟在身后
as he made his way through the Roman town square.
这个仆人唯一的工作就是
And this servant's only job
当别人赞美他时，在他耳边低声说
was to whisper in his ear when people praised him,
你只是个凡人 你只是个凡人
"You're only a man. You're only a man. "
- 好了，凡人 - 好吧，凡人
- Okay, man? - Okay, man.
- 好吧，凡人 - 那是胡扯
- Okay, man. - That's some bullshit.
讲得很好
That's good.
我认为你不理解这个故事的含义
Nick: I don't think you even know what that story means.
你没懂，尼克 他们说什么并不重要
You're missing the point, Nick. It doesn't matter what they say.
好吧，我懂了
Okay, I got this now.
好吧，女士们先生们 一个个来
All right, ladies and gentlemen, one at a time, one at a time.
那么你们会要求死刑？
So you'll be seeking the death penalty?
- 对于鲁柏特・阿米，我们会 - 那多比呢？
- For Rupert Ames, we will be. - And for Darby?
他已经承认谋杀 但他是个污点证人
He has pled guilty to murder, but he is a cooperating witness.
地方检察院已经动用了一切资源
The DA's office has committed all of its resources
确保司法公正
to ensure that justice will be served.
你们有没有做一些…
Woman: Did you make any kind of-
你觉得对多比而言是一个合理的宣判？
Man: Do you think this is a fair sentence for Darby?
我只想为你站在我的这边说声谢谢
I just wanted to say thanks for being in my corner.
司法体系运作时很不错，对吧？
It's nice when the system works, right?
离我远点
Get away from me.
走，走
Officer: Move. Move.
我们走吧
Let's go.
- 尼克？ - 嗨
- Nick? - Hey.
嗯，怎么了？
Nuh-uh, what happened?
什么怎么了？
What happened to what?
怎么了？
What's wrong?
你称我的工作乏味，C-？
You call my job boring. "C-"?
是的
Yes.
嗯，好了，现在…
Well... okay now...
你得告诉我怎么了？
you gonna tell me what's wrong?
我可以先跟我女儿聊一会吗？
Can I talk to my daughter for a little bit?
- 哦，拜托，别，别 - 我要躺下了
- Oh, please. No no no. - Gonna lay down.
拜托了
Please?
首先，这是你父亲在讲话
First of all, this is your father speaking.
- 哦，她不会知道 - 你怎么知道
- Yeah, she didn't know that. - You never know.
我想要你尽量呆在里面
I want you to stay in there as long as you can.
因为外面有很多疯子和混蛋
'cause there's a lot of crazy-ass people out here.
措辞…
Language.
你妈妈是个难缠的人物，但…
Your mother's a hardass, but-
我在场呢
I'm right here.
爸爸…爸爸想要你出来当爸爸的小女孩
And Daddy- Daddy wants you to come out and be Daddy's little girl.
我要她出来 因为她压在我的膀胱上
Woman: I want her to come out 'cause she's on my bladder.
啊
Nick: Ahh!
谁看到我的手机了吗？ （十年后）
Anybody seen my phone?
- 嘿，你看到我手机了吗？ - 没拴在你的手上吗？
- Hey, have you seen my phone? - It's not strapped to your hand?
没，没拴在我手上
No, it's not strapped to my hand.
- 爸爸 - 嗯？
- Daddy? - Yeah?
不打算吃点我做的法式吐司吗？
You're not gonna have some of my French toast?
- 法式吐司，你在做法式吐司？ - 嗯
- French toast? You made French toast? - Mm-hmm.
我不吃了，亲爱的 我就要迟到了
I can't, honey. I'm running late.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，来一口…嗯
All right, here- Mmm.
- 嗯，味道很不错 - 谢谢
- Mmm, that's good. - Thank you.
- 你自己做的？ - 嗯
- You did this by yourself? - Mm-hmm.
我要把这一盘都带到单位去
I'm just gonna take this whole plate to work.
嗯…不行
All right- no.
你才十岁吗？
You're only 10 years old?
- 比你妈做得还好吃 - 我听到了
- You better than your mother. - I heard that.
很香呀
Smells good in here. Your lifeline.
早安，宝贝 亲一个
'Morning, baby. Give me a kiss.
嗯!下午去你女儿的独奏会吗？
Mmm! You going to your daughter's recitaI this afternoon?
我还以为你会带演奏会DVD回来看呢
Um, I thought you were gonna order the DVDs.
看视频可不一样，尼克
Video's not the same, Nick.
妈妈，没关系 爸爸得工作，我理解
Mom, it's okay. Dad's got to work, I know.
瞧？没关系，爸爸得工作 那么老爸今天做什么？
See? It's all right. Dad's got to work. And what is Dad doing today?
- 把坏蛋关起来 - 那他为何那样做？
- Lock up bad guys. - And why does he do that?
- 来保护我们的安全 - 对了
- To keep us safe. - Yeah.
她理解 因为他想我们安安全全的
She understands. 'Cause he wants us to be safe.
- 宝贝，拿你的大提琴 - 好
- Baby, get your cello. - All right.
- 非常感谢 - 不客气
- Thank you so much. - You're welcome.
- 小朱莉娅宝贝 - 唔
- Little Julia Child. - Mmm.
你知道她才十岁，对吧？
You know she's 10 years old, right?
- 你知道吗？ - 当然
- You know that? - I know that.
她无法理解你为何不在身边
She doesn't understand why you're never around.
好人，坏人… 你就只会对她讲这些话
This good-guy, bad-guy stuff- that's just talk to her.
别这样了，好吧
Don't do this, come on.
我今天不能去
I can't come today.
你知道你连她的一次独奏会都没去过
You know you have not been to one recitaI-
- 她演了多少次了？ - 行了
- How many has she had? - Enough.
好了 好吧，我们会要视频回来
Okay. Well, we'll get the video,
我们坐下，然后一家人一起看
we'll sit down and we'll watch it together as a family.
我爱你
I love you.
好吧？
All right?
- 谢谢你的吐司 - 我爱你！
- Thank you for the toast. - Love you.
- 我也爱你！ - 拜
- Love you too! - Bye.
我爱你
Love you.
哼
Huh.
- 奇普怎样了？ - 切斯特了
- So how's Chip? - It's Chester.
奇普哪去了？ 我喜欢奇普
What happened to Chip? I liked Chip.
没奇普了
There is no Chip.
现在也不是切斯特 只是他不停打电话
And now there's no Chester. He kept calling.
- 莎拉，这是好事 - 我知道，但我一直拒绝
- Sarah, that's a good thing. - I know, but I kept cancelling.
我的案子太多了
My caseload's crazy.
你知道如果你不想跟这个案子 你可以不来
You know you don't have to go to this if you don't want to.
是的，我懂，我…
Yeah, I do. I...
是什么感觉？
What's it like?
没什么 像看着某人睡着
No biggie. Like watching somebody fall asleep.
除了叫不醒这步骤
Except for the not-waking-up part.
还在困扰你吗？
Does it bother you?
再也不会了
Not anymore.
莎拉，你穿高跟鞋真得好看
Sarah, your legs are looking real good in those heels.
滚开
Fuck off.
你来干嘛，雷诺斯？ 你为何在这，你的DVD坏了吗？
What are you doing here, Reynolds? Your DVD player broken?
阿米没有亲人，我觉得有人应该为他而来
Ames has no family. I felt like someone should be here for him.
哦，你真好
Wow, that's nice.
吸气
Breathe.
鲁柏特・阿米，你还有什么要说的么？
Rupert Ames, do you have anything you want to say?
是的
Yeah.
呃
Uh-huh.
我做的是错事
Ames: What I did that night was wrong.
我不该去那的
I should have never been there.
但我向天发誓 我没有杀害那些人
But I swear to God, I didn't kill those people.
今天这里死的人搞错了
The wrong man's dying here today.
The wrong man's dying.
就这些
That's all.
看着我
Look at me.
看着我！
Look at me!
啊！靠！
Ahh! Fuck!
靠！
Fuck!
啊！靠！
Ahh! Fuck!
哦，天那
Oh, God.
- 哦，天呀 - 带她…带她出去
- Oh, God. - Take her- take her out.
- 到底怎么回事 - 我不知道
- What the hell is going on? - I don't know.
啊！
Ahhh!
是什么引起犯人这种意外的反应？
Man: What could have caused the unexpected reaction of the inmate?
我们会给你消息的
We'll keep you informed.
你没事吧？啊?
You okay? Huh?
嗯
Yeah.
有人杀了那个你本想杀的人？
So somebody killed the guy you were trying to kill?
这个叫什么来着？
What are we calling this?
明显违反第8修正案赋予他的权利
Clear violation of his Eighth Amendment rights-
- 残忍与非正当刑罚 - 法学院…
- cruel and unusual punishment. - Law schooI.
嗯，那机器…平时是如何运作的？
Yeah. The machine- how does it work on a good day?
它是按无痛设计的
It's designed to be pain-free.
按特定的程序注射三剂药物
It's three drugs administered in a specific order.
基于这点，我们应该假设…
From this point on, we're operating under the assumption
机器被动了手脚
that the machine was corrupted.
我们需要所有能接近那机器的人员名单
We're gonna need a list of all the people with access to that machine.
- 我的人不会干这种事的 - 我能理解，典狱长
- My people would not do this. - I appreciate that, Warden,
但我不只要通行证和请假条之类的
but I'm gonna need more than a hall pass and a note from Mom.
探长，机器后面发现了这个
Detectives, got this off the back of the machine.
- 你看看 - 我看看
- Check it out. - Let me see it.
在那
Man: Right there.
“没法跟天斗”
"Can't fight fate. "
尼克，怎么了？
Cantrell: What is it, Nick?
在入室侵犯时，阿米的同伙
During the home invasion, Ames's accomplice
曾对其中一名受害者说 “你没法跟天斗”这话
said to one of the vics, "You can't fight fate. "
他在法庭上也和我说过同样的话
And then he said the same thing to me in the courtroom- prick.
但我记不得他的名字了
I can't remember his name, though.
看一下这个…是你们要找的人吗？
Detective: Have a look at this- your guy?
- 克拉伦斯・詹姆士・多比 - 他是个人渣
- Nick: Clarence James Darby. - Detective: He's a cutie.
- 你跟他有关系？ - 放了他一马
- You got history with him? - Nick: Put him away.
恩，才三年 现在杀人才关这么短吗？
All right, three years. That the going rate for murder these days?
有减刑的情况
There was extenuating circumstances.
唯一减刑的情况是他没干这事
The only extenuating circumstances should be he didn't do it.
还是在马里恩监狱待了三年 该死的角斗士学院
Still, three years at Marion? Fucking gladiator academy.
你指望他变成模范市民？
You expect him to come back a modeI citizen?
好了，如果你们这帮学者 没污染犯罪现场的话
Well, if you scholars wouldn't contaminate the crime scenes,
我能把他们关久一点
I could keep them locked up longer.
当局拒绝对此发表评论
TV reporter: Authorities have refused to comment at this point,
但不排除有违规的行为
but foul play cannot be ruled out.
该罪犯已经在死囚区待了10年…
The prisoner had been on death row for the past 10 years-
他的名字是鲁珀特・阿米
his name, Rupert Ames.
我们所知道的一点是
Female reporter: All we know at this point
本应该是无痛行刑
is what was supposed to be a painless execution
变成了恐怖片中的情景
has turned into something out of a horror film.
喂？
Yeah?
- 克拉伦斯・多比？ - 谁？
- Disguised voice: Clarence Darby? - Who's this?
三样关于你的:桌上的可卡因
That's strike three for you: coke on the table,
地板上的婊子…监狱里的生活
bitch on the floor- life in prison.
你他妈是谁？
Who the fuck is this?
看看窗外…南边
Voice: Look out your window, south side.
- 开玩笑吗？起来！ - 啊！
- Is this a joke? Get up! - Ahh!
南边
South side.
他妈的
Motherfucker.
靠，别挡路！
Shit. Out of the way!
- 蹲下！ - 你们都疯了！
- Stay down! - You're all crazy!
他往北去了 快上，上
He's heading north! Go go!
- 该死 - 快去，快去，走
- Damn. - Move it, move it. Go on!
- 现在怎么做？ - 擦掉枪上的指纹
- What now? - Wipe the prints off the gun.
- 然后把枪丢掉 - 不，不
- Get rid of it. - No no.
你开了六枪了，天才 你带了弹药了么？
You fired six times, genius. You bring any ammunition?
- 扔了吧 - 你为什么这样做？
- Lose it. - Why are you doing this?
我不想让你进监狱
I want to keep you out of prison.
看到那废弃的工厂了吗？ 去那
See the abandoned factories? Go toward them.
为什么？
Why?
那里有辆警车，车内有个警察
There's a cop car there with a cop in it.
该死的怎么回事？
What the fuck?
我电晕了他，但他在90秒内就会醒来
I Tasered him, but he'll be waking up in about 90 seconds,
所以你最好快点
so you'd better move.
起来了，你这个贱人 快他妈起来！
Rise and fucking shine, bitch. Wake the fuck up!
我们走！ 快他妈开车！
Let's go! Start the fucking car!
- 好的！ - 快点
- Okay! - Do it.
- 别冲动，别冲动… - 快点！
- Take it easy, take it- - Come on!
- 好，我们走 - 别冲动
- Okay, let's go. - Take it easy.
我们走，挂档呀 笨蛋，现在！
Let's go! Get in gear, shithead, now!
现在！走，走，快走！
Do it! Go go go!
他妈滚出去！
Get the fuck out.
快走吧！
Let's go.
给我趴到那边去
Get the fuck down there!
那么，我妻子怎么办？ 我的小女儿？
Okay. What about my wife? My little girl?
- 我再也见不到她们了 - 惨极了，是吧？
- I'll never see them again. - Fucked up, ain't it?
哦，哦，哦
Oh oh oh.
不介意我接个电话吧？
You don't mind if I take this, do you?
我的守护天使
My guardian angel.
我深为感激
I am impressed.
你知道我为什么再也见不到我妻女了吗？
You know why I'll never see my wife and little girl again?
因为你夺走了她们的性命
'Cause you took 'em from me.
记得我吗？
You remember me?
你当然记得
Sure you do.
你以前曾经去过我家
You came over to my house once before.
你不记得了？
You don't remember?
这河豚毒素…
This tetrodotoxin...
应该很好地进入你的体内了
should be nicely into your system by now.
这是从加勒比河豚鱼的肝脏提取出来的
It's isolated from the liver of a Caribbean puffer fish.
所以它麻痹了你
So it paralyzes you,
但保留了其它神经功能
but leaves all the other neurological functions
…完好无损
perfectly intact.
换句话说，你没法动弹了…
In other words, you can't move...
但你可以感觉到一切
but you feel everything.
它不会减轻你一丁点痛苦
It does absolutely nothing to blunt the pain.
而你即将体验
And you're about to experience more of that
你根本无法想象到的
than you could ever fucking imagine.
这是止血带
These are tourniquets
这样你就不会流血 因为你可能要在这待上一阵
so you don't bleed out, 'cause you may be here a while.
生理盐水…
Saline solution-
应该能让我们继续下去
that should keep us going.
绑上皮带…安全牢固
Clamps- nice and secure.
舒服吧？
Comfortable?
你真的在发抖
You really are shaking.
确定你没事？
Sure you're all right?
你会爱上这个的…
You'll love this-
肾上腺素
adrenaline.
现在注射这个，你就不会晕过去了
Now this is so you don't pass out.
来吧
There you go.
感觉怎样？很好吧？
How's that feel? Good?
现在我可不希望你吞下你的舌头
Now what we don't want is you swallowing your tongue,
所以陪着我吧
so bear with me.
这是为你的老二准备的 但我们稍后再做
Now this is for your penis, but we'll get to that later.
手术刀…
Scalpel...
割双眼皮用的
for your eyelids,
万一你中途他妈的闭上眼睛
in case you insist on fucking shutting them.
你瞧
You see,
我知道无助绝望的滋味
I know what it feels like to be helpless.
就如我看着你屠杀我全家一样
just like when I watched you slaughter my whole family.
你知道你没法跟天斗 对吧，多比？
You know you can't fight fate, right, Darby?
哦！
Oh!
你看… 我还特别为你准备了这个
And look- I made this especially for you.
喜欢么？ 嗯，我不想让你错过一切
You like it? Yeah, I didn't want you to miss anything.
现在你处在屋里最好的观赏位置
Now you have the best view in the house.
你听到了吗？
You hear that?
你的心脏跳得很快
Your heart is beating so fast.
哦，我也是
No, me too.
好了
Okay.
现在她们能看到你受折磨了
Now they get to watch you suffer.
她们将是你最后看到的东西
They'll be the last thing you ever see
当我切断你该死的四肢时
as I cut off every single one of your fucking limbs.
看，我没撒谎
See, I wasn't lying
我说过我不希望你进监狱
when I told you that I wanted to keep you out of prison.
都是实话
That was the truth.
谢谢你的车
Thanks for the car.
好了，这是有关多比的所有案件档案
Sarah: Okay, these are all the case files on Darby.
我尽力调查了 我们有犯罪现场的照片
I vetted through what I could. We have crime-scene photos-
不需要看了，嗯
Don't need to see 'em.
好的
Okay.
- 什么事困扰你？ - 多比
- What's bothering you? - It's Darby.
他所犯的罪行都有一个共同点
All the crimes he's committed have one thing in common,
那就是暴力 但昨天行刑现场
and that was violence. But yesterday at that execution,
- 并非暴力，而是… - 是什么？
- that wasn't violence. That was- - What?
- 是智力 - 好吧
- That was intellect. - Okay.
- 你在想什么？ - 我也不知道
- What are you thinking? - I don't know.
我只是在想我们不应该再查多比
I'm just thinking maybe we shouldn't be looking for Darby.
我的老天
Jesus Christ.
瑞斯
Rice.
好消息，检察官 找到多比了
Detective: Good news, Counselor. We found Darby.
不过我得说一句 还不如以前好看
I gotta say though, he's looked better.
他们发现他被肢解成25块
Sarah: They found him in about 25 pieces:
没有腿，没有手臂 眼脸被割了…真可怕
no legs, no arms, eyelids were sliced off- gruesome.
- 为多比掉泪？ - 不至于
- Nick: Shedding tears for Darby? - Not quite.
- 我看到你眼睛打转了 - 想想谁有动机
- Cantrell: I see your wheels turning. - Nick: Think motive- who has one?
那个丈夫、父亲 我们对他了解多少？
Cantrell: The husband, the father. What do we know about him?
警方发现多比的那间仓库是他的
He owned the warehouse where they found Darby.
- 还有呢？ - 他是一个工匠
- What else? - He's a tinkerer-
小发明家，发明了一些东西 他持有一些专利
uh, little inventions, gizmos. He holds two dozen patents
赚了不少钱
that made him some money.
几年前，他卖了大部分财产
He liquidated most of his wealth a few years ago
买了些临近机场、化学工厂
to buy some industrial properties around airports,
和铁道场附近的院子
chemical plants, raiI yards.
- 这不合理 - 没错，很古怪，是吧？
- It doesn't add up. - No, it's weird, right?
全部都搜查，莎拉 看看能找到什么
Search 'em all, Sarah. See what you find.
不许动！
Freeze!
- 跪下，快！ - 跪下！
- Get down, go! - On your knees!
- 脸朝下，脸朝下 - 把他按下去铐起来
- Face down, face down! - Pull him down and cuff him!
这个疯子吓到我了
Crazy men scare the shit out of me.
这家伙是个律师吗？
Detective: Is this guy a lawyer?
不
No.
他是一个工程师
He's an engineer.
尼克，看看这个 （美国法典：注释版）
Sarah: Nick, look at this.
我们没有半点证据 需要他坦白认罪
Cantrell: We have zero evidence. Gonna need a confession.
他来的路中有没有给你们造成麻烦？
He give you any trouble on the way in?
不，没有
No, nothing.
我们拿走他手链时，他不太高兴
He wasn't too happy when we took his bracelet, though.
- 什么事？ - 瑞斯家的包裹
- Can I help you? - Package for the Rice family.
哦，好的，谢谢
Oh, yeah. Thanks.
妈妈，我独奏会的影带送来了 我们可以看了吗？
Mom, the video from my recital came. Can we watch it?
- 拜托啦？ - 不，现在不行
- Please? - No, not you.
不，我们说过要等爸爸回来一起看的 记得么？
No, please, we said we were gonna wait for your father, remember?
- 拜托了？ - 不，现在不行
- Please? - No, not now.
好吧
Okay.
啊哈，好的
Uh-huh, yes.
好的，肯定的
Yes, absolutely.
妈妈！
Mommy!
别担心，他只是在消除这家伙的戒心 让他放轻松些
Don't worry, he's just disarming the guy, letting him feeI easy.
我要跟你说的话 不希望有其他任何人听见
What I'm about to tell you I don't want anybody else to hear.
身为检察官，我现在要打破所有原则
As a prosecutor, I'm breaking all the rules right now,
我不管那一套 因为我是一个父亲
and I don't give a damn because I'm a father.
我有个女儿
I have a little girl.
而你干的…棒极了
And what you did... bravo.
没有多比和阿米的世界会更美好
The world is better without Darby and Ames.
你不会看到我或我的人流一滴泪
You're not gonna see a tear shed from me or anybody in my office.
说完这些…
With that being said...
我该办正事了
I have a job to do.
我将会问你一些非常简单而直接的问题
I'm gonna ask you some very simple and direct questions.
我建议你也用同样的方式回答
I suggest that you answer them in the same fashion.
你叫克莱德・亚历山大・谢尔顿吗？
Is your name Clyde Alexander Shelton?
是的，先生
Yes, sir.
而你已经放弃请律师的权利，对吧？
And you've waived your right to counsel, correct?
- 是的，先生 - 你确定你想这样做吗？
- Yes, sir. - You sure you want to do that?
是的
Yes.
是你谋杀了克拉伦斯・多比吗
Did you murder Clarence Darby?
我想过要他死
I wanted him dead.
他杀了我的妻子和孩子
He killed my wife and child.
鲁珀特… 你也杀了他吗？
Rupert Ames- did you murder him as well?
鲁珀特・阿米该死
Rupert Ames deserved to die.
他们都该死
They both deserved to die.
那么你策划过这两起谋杀案？
So you arranged both of those murders?
恩，我计划过…
Yes, I planned it...
在我的头脑里，一遍又一遍 花了很长的时间
in my head, over and over again. It took me a long time.
好吧
All right.
我想我们的对话结束了
I guess we're done here.
检察官？
Counselor?
估计你要取消跟罗伯茨法官12点半的午餐了
You might want to canceI your 12:30 lunch with Judge Roberts.
什么？
Excuse me?
实际上，你大概要取消本周余下的行程了
In fact, you might want to cancel the rest of the week,
因为你会相当忙 坐下吧
'cause you're gonna be busy. Sit down.
我们这问完了 我们有了你的供词
We're done here. We have your confession.
嗯，哦，完了？
Mmm. Oh, you do?
录音带里
On tape.
瞧，在我们这行里 我们称那为“灌篮”
See, in our profession, we consider that a slam-dunk.
哦，真的吗？ 我不认为，让我们回想一下
Oh, really? I don't think so. Let's think back.
我说什么了？
What did I say?
我说我想过克拉伦斯・多比死？
That I wanted to kill Clarence Darby?
是的，当然 哪个父亲不想呢？
Yeah, sure. What father wouldn't?
多比和阿米都该死
That both Darby and Ames deserved to die?
我想大部分人都会认同那点
I think most people would agree with that.
我在脑子里一遍又一遍地计划过这件事
That I planned it over and over again in my head?
是呀，谁不会幻想那样呢？
Yeah. Who wouldn't fantasize about that?
这些没一句是承认罪行，尼克
None of these are an admission of guilt, Nick.
- 你或许想检查一下带子 - 我们知道是你干的
- You might want to check the tape. - We know you did it.
可这与你知道什么无关 而是你能在法庭上证明什么
Well, it's not what you know, it's what you can prove in court.
这不是你曾跟我讲过的话吗？
Didn't you tell me that once?
你理论的唯一毛病是
The only problem with your theory
多比的尸体是在你名下土地上发现的
is that Darby's body was found on your property.
我名下许多土地中的一个… 一座老旧的废弃仓库，尼克
One of my many properties- an old abandoned warehouse, Nick.
吸毒者，他们常常擅自闯进去
Junkies, they trespass there all the time.
多比不会牵涉毒品交易吗？
Isn't Darby involved in the drug trade?
那是一个沉沦的世界 我打赌陪审团会认同的
That's an unsavory world. I bet you a jury would agree.
或者某人试图嫁祸于我
Or perhaps someone was trying to frame me.
知道吧，克莱德
You know, Clyde,
牢里有很多混蛋自认为比我聪明
there's a lot of assholes in prison that thought they were smarter than me.
我们别再扯谈了
Let's stop fucking around.
尼克，除非你有铁证
Nick, unless you have any hard evidence,
否则我们为何在这？ 我们为何在这谈话
then why are we even here? Why are we having this-
你想要什么？
- What do you want? - -conversation?
好，很简单
Well, that's easy.
现在你是那个和谋杀犯做交易的人了，对吧？
Now you're the one who makes deals with murderers, yeah?
那我就要提出我的条件了
So I've come to make mine.
我会给你一个坦白 一个真正的坦白
I will give you a confession, a reaI confession.
你只需要给我东西作为回报
You just have to give me something in return.
哦，好吧，你已经是个谋杀犯了 还想要什么呢？
Yeah, well, since you are a murderer, what might that be?
一张床
A bed.
得是一张好床
But a nice bed.
我要给自己一张舒适的床
I want a nice new one for my cell.
很简单
Very simple.
你一定得办好 因为现在的床凹凸不平，尼克
You're gonna have to deal with that, because the one I have is lumpy, Nick.
快令我抓狂了
It's making me crazy.
克莱德，跟谨小慎微的人打交道让我很烦
Clyde, I think you've got me confused with detail people.
所以，我不管你牢房里的条件
See, I don't deaI with prison conditions.
我想牢房里的床用螺丝固定住了
I believe those cots are bolted into the cells.
那就是扳手的作用，蠢驴
Well, that's what wrenches are for, dumbass.
你知道，有一种达西安娜床
You know, one of those new Duxiana beds
带有调整…你知道 那种调整腰椎支撑的床吧
with the adjustable- you know, adjustable lumbar support,
- 就是那种 - 我看过那广告
- that's the one. - I've seen the commercial.
- 我要的就是那种 - 那种床不错
- That's the one I want. - Those are nice.
- 因为真的… - 夜里晚些时候
- 'Cause really- - Comes on late at night.
- 坦白讲我认为… - 两个老年人躺在床上
- And frankly I don't think- - Two old people laying on the bed.
我没法专注于任何事情
- I'll be able to focus on anything
除非在那张有疗效的达西安那床上
untiI I've had a good revitalizing night's sleep
我晚上睡个安稳的好觉
in my therapeutic Duxiana bed.
这就是交易
So that's the deal:
你给我要的床 我就对你坦白
you get me my bed, you get your confession.
好吧，让我考虑一下
Okay, let me think about that for a second.
这个怎么样…
How about...
他妈的不行
fuck no.
喂，你在干吗？
Hey, what are you doing?
- 什么意思？ - 你为什么拒绝他？
- What do you mean? - Why did you tell him no?
席梦思床？那不是他说的算的
A mattress? He doesn't make those kinds of decisions.
别太自我了，尼克 希尔顿说对了一点，这个案子没证据
Take your ego out of it, Nick. Shelton's got a point: this case is shit.
我们需要他坦白 一张席梦思床换一个杀人犯的供词
We need a confession. And a mattress for a murder confession?
- 这是个非常划算的买卖 - 他在耍我们，乔纳斯
- That's a pretty good deal. - He's playing us, Jonas.
恩，接下来是我们玩他了
Well, then we will play him.
尼克?
Nick?
办公室有急电找你 他们说你不接你手机
There's an urgent call from your office. They say you're not answering your cell.
我得打理完这里的事情 然后尽快回家
I need to finish up here and then I will be home as soon as I can.
听我说，这个录影带上的东西…
Listen to me: the things on this video-
尼克，我从未见过的…
Nick, I have never seen anything like it.
求你快点回家吧
Please come home.
听着，你得冷静下来 告诉她那不是真的…
Listen, you need to calm down. Tell her that it's not real...
- 好的 - 告诉她，我爱她
- Okay. - ... and that I love her.
回家吧，求你快点回家
Come home. Come home soon, please.
- 凯莉，你有看到他的脸吗？ - 没有
- Kelly, did you see his face? - No.
用东西遮住了 我看不到
It was covered with something. I couldn't see.
好的，宝贝，让我忙完这边 我就马上回去了，好吧？
Okay, baby, let me finish up here and I'll come home as fast as I can, okay?
好的
Okay.
这个混蛋寄了一张他杀多比的DVD到我家里
This motherfucker sent a DVD to my house of him killing Darby.
- 什么? - 我女儿看到了
- What? - My daughter saw it.
他录下来了？ 我们抓到他了
He recorded it? We've got him.
不，没有，他带着面具 我们需要他认罪
No no, he had on a mask. We need that confession.
你还想和这个人讨价还价吗？
You still want to bargain with this man?
典狱长，一切皆有可能
The art of the possible, Warden.
做这笔交易吧
Make the deal.
喂，来啊，哥们！也给我一张！
Man: Hey, come on, man! Give us one!
后背毛病，典狱长 最难受了
Back problems, Warden- the worst.
有比那严重的问题
You got bigger problems than that.
所有人都没有的东西，孩子
It's the have-nots in here, son.
换了是我，我知道我可不想有
I don't know that I want to be the one "have. "
转身
Turn around.
我认为他不喜欢我
I don't think he likes me.
床不错
Nice bed.
谢谢
Thank you.
是单人的
It's a single.
我要在这小心我的后背了，听到了吗？
I'd watch my fucking back around here, you hear?
进监房，去吧
In the cell, let's go.
我们到处都找不到克莱德・谢尔顿的马脚
We can't put Clyde Shelton anywhere-
工作中，城市里，甚至整个国家都没有
not in a job, not in a city, not even the country.
所以我深挖了一下 从他失踪的几年里我发现了些事情
So I dug a little deeper and I found something from his missing years:
国防部有两笔契约款汇给了克莱德
a couple of contract payments to Clyde from the Department of Defense.
- 他的不动产呢？ - 他买了九处不动产
- And his real estate? - He bought nine properties
登记在他的名下 然后他将这些资产…
under his own name, then he transferred them
转到巴拿马的某间公司
to some corporation in Panama.
由于缺乏互助条款，
We can't get to the addresses.
我们无法得到地址
A lack of reciprocity is our problem.
我们绕了个圈又回到了农舍
So I'm gonna circle back to the farmhouse.
那是浪费时间 他本来就想让我们找到他在那里
That's a waste of time. He wanted us to find it and find him there.
那些工业用品倒令人感兴趣
It's the industrial stuff that's curious.
好了，我不管你们要做什么 或着你们要得罪谁
All right, I don't care what you have to do and who you have to piss off.
如果我们得再次入侵巴拿马，好吧
If we have to invade Panama again, fine.
克莱德隐藏这些财产是有理由的 给我找出来
Clyde is hiding those properties for a reason. Find him.
明白
Got it.
- 宝贝，你有留了一条缝吗？ - 嗯？是的，我留了一条缝
- Baby, you leave it cracked? - Hmm? Yeah, I left it cracked.
- 夜灯呢？ - 她这么大了还开夜灯是不是…？
- Night light? - Isn't she too old for a night light?
嗯，我开夜灯了
Yeah, I left a night light.
- 很好 - 听着
- Good. - Look,
我告诉她视频不是真的
I told her that that video wasn't real.
- 好 - 那只是恐怖片
- Okay. - It's some sort of horror film-
某种她不该看的恐怖片
something she shouldn't be looking at anyway.
- 好，很好 - 她会没事的
- Okay, good. - She'll be okay.
嗯，那你呢？
Yeah. And you?
- 我怎样？好吗？ - 是的
- Am I what? Okay? - Yeah.
当然，我看起来像有事么？
Of course. Don't I look okay?
- 嗯？ - 嗯
- Hmm? - Yeah.
尼克总是没事的
Nick is always okay.
我总是非常好
Always- I'm extra good.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
鉴于谢尔顿先生的经济状况
In light of Mr. Shelton's economic means
和潜在的逃亡风险
and his potential flight risk,
加上阿米和多比先生死于非命
the egregious nature of both Mr. Ames's and Mr. Darby's deaths,
请求将保释驳回，法官阁下
the state requests that bail be denied, Your Honor.
谢尔顿先生，既然你放弃了你律师的权利
Judge: Seeing as how you've...
你有什么想说的？
waived your right to counsel, Mr. Shelton,
do you have anything to say?
谢尔顿先生？
Mr. Shelton?
你有任何话想说吗？谢尔顿…
Do you have anything that you'd like to say, Mr. Shelton?
是的，是的，是的，法官阁下
Yes yes yes, Your Honor.
- 我用站起来吗？ - 请吧
- Should I stand? - Please.
法官阁下，我是一个守法公民
Your Honor, I'm a law-abiding citizen.
只是一个平凡的人
I'm just a regular guy.
我不是一个会逃跑的人
I am not a flight risk.
这是我第一次被控违法
And this is my first alleged offense.
而且检方没有呈出任何一样对我不利的证据
And the prosecution has not presented one single piece of evidence against me.
在此情况下
Now in these circumstances,
除非检方找到了新的情报
unless the state has obtained some new piece of information
关于我牵涉到目前讨论的案子
relating to my involvement in the matter in question,
否则我会觉得扣押我并不准保释
then I find it highly prejudiciaI, even constitutionally offensive,
是种很严重的偏见
to keep me detained without bail.
这是一种倒退，法官阁下
It's a slippery slope, Your Honor.
难道我们没见过这种暴行的后果吗
Haven't we seen the result of such violations,
不管是在国内还是国外
both internationally and domestically? Case in point
比如戴夫-麦唐纳案子 档案编号041325
would be Day v. McDonough, docket #041325.
我事实上…倾向于同意你，谢尔顿先生
I am actually inclined to agree with you, Mr. Shelton.
法官阁下，谢尔顿先生已经同意 向我们认罪了
Your Honor, Mr. Shelton has agreed to give us a full confession.
他已经认罪了吗？瑞斯先生
Has he given it, Mr. Rice?
没有，法官阁下
No, Your Honor.
那么就我看来
Well, then in my opinion,
检方没有令人信服的证据
the state has failed to establish a compelling basis
来限制他的行动自由 我将同意保释，保释金为…
for its motion, and I will grant bail in the amount of-
法官阁下 我想提醒您别这样做
Your Honor, I would caution you not to do that.
谢谢
Thank you.
什么？
Excuse me?
不，我想我不会为你开脱的
No, I don't think I will excuse you.
你瞧我说的意思是
You see, this is what I'm talking about.
你刚刚准备放我走 你在开玩笑吗？
You were about to let me go. Are you kidding me?
我们在这里最开始是为什么
This is why we're here in the first place.
你以为我不记得你是谁了，夫人？
You think I don't remember who you are, lady?
谢尔顿先生，我会小心谨慎地
I would tread carefully, Mr. Shelton.
哦，那么我该如何小心谨慎？
Well, how carefully should I tread?
因为显然地我刚杀了两个人
Because apparently I just killed two people,
而你却准备让我走出那道门！
and you were about to let me walk right out that door!
你是多么误导别人？
How misguided are you?
我随便拿出一两个合法的案例唬你
I feed you a couple of bullshit legal precedents,
你就…你就像个火辣的婊子一样扑过来
and there you go- you jump on it like a bitch in heat.
- 朋友们，你们都窝在… - 我警告你，谢尔顿先生
- Folks, you all hang out- - I'm warning you, Mr. Shelton!
- 同一个小俱乐部里 - 你会被控诉藐视法庭
- -in the same little club. - You will be held in contempt!
每天你让疯子和谋杀犯回到大街上
And every day you let madmen and murderers back on the street.
- 你太忙于教条判案 - 再次警告！
- You're too busy treating the law- - One more time!
- 就像该死的生产线一样 - 再次警告！
- -like it's a fucking assembly line! - One more time.
- 你知道什么叫公正吗？ - 你现在…
- Do you have any idea what justice is? - You are now-
- 不管什么是对与错！ - 被控以藐视法庭！
- Whatever happened to right and wrong? - -in contempt of court.
- 不管什么是对与错！ - 把他押下去！
- Whatever happened to right and wrong? - Remove this man.
- 不管别人发生什么！ - 保释驳回！
- Whatever happened to the people? - Bail denied!
- 不管什么公正！ - 保释驳回！
- Whatever happened to justice? - Bail denied!
我打赌你都把它塞在屁眼里了
And I bet you take it up the fucking ass, bitch.
法警！
Bailiff.
嗨，待会见，尼克
Clyde: Hey, see you later, Nick.
精神失常？
Nick: Insanity?
那就是你自我辩护的伎俩吗？ 精神失常？
That's what you're building your defense on? Insanity?
尼克，我告诉过你我会向你坦白
Nick, I told you I would give you a confession.
而我…是认真的
And I- I meant it.
- 我今天看了部电影 - 你看了？
- I saw a movie today. - You did?
我女儿也看了同一个
My daughter saw the same movie.
你告诉你女儿这是关于好人对坏人的么？
Well, you taught your daughter about good versus eviI?
没必要
I don't have to.
嗯，那部电影的主题就是邪不胜正
Well, that's what this movie was about: good conquering evil,
正义伸张 邪恶受惩
the righteous prospering, the wicked suffering.
我不明白
I didn't get that.
我会再给你一次机会，克莱德
I'm gonna give you one more chance, Clyde.
别考验我，因为我会跟你死耗
And don't test me 'cause I will run you over.
很公平
Fair enough.
你的确给了我要的床
You did get me my bed.
交易就是交易
A deal's a deal.
录影带上是你杀了克拉伦斯・多比 对吗？
That was you on video killing Clarence Darby, wasn't it?
是的，那是我
Yes, that was me.
好了，很公平 那是我，克莱德・谢尔顿
Okay, fair enough. That was me, Clyde Shelton,
录像里的人，杀死克拉伦斯・多比
on the video, killing Clarence Darby.
不够，克莱德，我需要细节
Not good enough, Clyde. I need specifics.
我用断线钳钳断他的手指
I took his fingers with bolt cutters,
用尖嘴钳剪断他的脚趾头
his toes with tin snips,
用钢锯锯下他的蛋蛋
his balls with a hacksaw,
用箱刀割下他的老二
and his penis with a box cutter.
这样够详细了吧？
How's that for specifics?
阿米呢？
And Ames?
调换筒罐很容易 今天一切都是自动化的
Switching the canisters was easy. Everything's automated these days,
我只需要入侵货运公司的服务器
so I just hacked into the shipping company's server
篡改几个数字，包裹就来到我这儿了
and swapped a few numbers around so the package came to me.
然后我用某种更有内涵的东西
Then I switched the potassium chloride
调换了…氯化钾
with something a little more... deliberate.
好了，我听够了你的狗屎
Well, I'm tired of hearing your bullshit.
我得到我想要的了
I got everything I need.
现在怎么办？
What now?
我回家，你进监狱
I go home; you go to prison.
你知道 正义必将伸张，邪恶必受罚
You know, the righteous prospering, the wicked suffering.
那应该会令你对司法体制感觉好些
That ought to make you feel better about the system.
如果我有其它要坦白的呢？
What if I had another confession to make?
向神父说吧
Call a priest.
可另一个坦白需要另一个交易，尼克
But another confession would mean another deal, Nick,
所以你必须给我点东西作为回报
so you would have to give me something in return.
你曾去过德菲斯可餐厅吗？ 他们送外卖
You ever been to Del Frisco's? They cater.
所以午餐我想吃20盎司的牛排
So for lunch, I would love a 20oz porterhouse steak,
五分熟，或许有点焦
medium, maybe a little bit charred,
加上一堆的配菜… 薯条、芦笋、奶油南瓜
with all the trimmings- pommes frites, asparagus, butter squash.
去你的，去你的薯条
Fuck you and your pommes frites.
我还要告诉你，可以把我的iPod拿来么？
I'll tell you what: can I have my iPod as well?
我喜欢用餐时来点音乐
I'd love a little bit of music with my meal.
谈判的首条原则，克莱德 你得有谈判的资本
First rule of negotiating, Clyde: you gotta have something to bargain with.
比尔・雷诺斯的命足够吗？
Would the life of Bill Reynolds suffice?
打开
Open it.
这该死的比尔・雷诺斯是谁？
Who the fuck is Bill Reynolds?
多比的律师
Darby's attorney.
跟我说你有他的下落了
Tell me you located him.
我联系上他妻子了 她三天前报案说他失踪了
I've got his wife. She reported him missing three days ago.
谢谢你，雷诺斯太太
Thank you, Mrs. Reynolds.
看来我终究还是有资本还价的，尼克
Clyde: Well, looks like I got something to bargain with after all, Nick.
现在比尔・雷诺斯依然活着
At the moment, Bill Reynolds is still alive.
我会告诉你他的确切位置
I'll tell you exactly where he is.
只要把我的午餐和音乐1点整带来
Just bring me my meal and my music at 1:00 exactly.
正好1点
00 sharp.
1点，尼克
00, Nick.
好，就停在那
That's good, right there.
好了，起来
All right, up!
- 已经12点55了 - 我不听命于他或者你
- It's 5 to 1:00. - I don't take orders from him or you.
囚犯不知道时间
And inmates don't have access to the time.
- 我们告诉他们几点就是几点 - 我不关心他是否有劳力士
- We tell them what time it is. - I don't care if he has a Rolex or not.
我们得遵守时间 我们答应过的时间
We need to stick to the timeline that was agreed to.
去他妈的，尼克，让他等
Fuck him, Nick. Let him wait.
老天，他锯掉了那家伙的老二
Christ, he sawed a guy's dick off.
不管你喜欢与否 我们要遵守他的时间
Whether you like it or not, we are on his time.
再检查一遍
Check it again.
你们就这么恶心我吗！
Inmate: Are you shitting me with this?!
这混蛋
This motherfucker!
快点！ 我快饿死了！
Man, come on! I'm fucking hungry!
蒸芦笋
Steamed asparagus,
- 龙虾通心粉和奶酪 - 喔
- lobster macaroni and cheese... - Wow.
上等腰肉牛排 焦的，五成熟
...porterhouse steak, seared, medium rare.
嗯！
Mmm!
嗯
Hmm.
- 餐巾纸，尼克 - 餐巾纸
- Napkin, Nick. - Napkin.
哦，麻烦你了，服务生
Oh, excuse me, waiter?
你拿百分之三十做小费
You might want to put 30% down for yourself, my man.
- 喂，几点了？ - 1点了
- Hey, what time is it? - It's 1:00.
时间对吗，尼克？
Is that right, Nick?
- 1点08分 - 真让人失望，典狱长
- It's 1:08. - That's disappointing, Warden.
我是说，如果你们都对我不实在
I mean, how can you expect me not to fuck with you
怎能保证我不耍你们呢
when you can't even be honest with me?
克莱德，你要的事情都办到了 现在，雷诺斯在哪？
Late or not, Clyde, you have what you asked for. Now where's Reynolds?
绅士们，我能拿个银制餐具吗？
Can I have some silverware, gentlemen?
银制餐具
Silverware.
给你一只叉匙
You get a spork.
白痴
Idiot.
谢谢
Thanks.
好了，克莱德
Come on, Clyde.
好吧
Okay.
我们来吧
Here we go:
北纬39度57分04
39N57'...04",
东经75度10分22
075W10'22".
你最好快点，尼克
And you'd better hurry, Nick.
因为除了典狱长的时间 其他人的时间已经晚了
'Cause by anybody's watch but the warden's, you're already late.
- 开门 - 混蛋们，我的午餐呢？
- Open the door! - Inmate: Where's my lunch?
我带一支地面小队过去
I'll take a ground unit!
我猜如果我不跟你分享这个的话 你会…
So I suppose if I don't share this with you, you're gonna-
我会他妈站起来
I'm gonna get the fuck up,
举起我的右手
I'm gonna cock back my right hand,
把你的脑瓜劈成两半，那样如何？
and I'm gonna split your whole fucking skull in two. How about that?
好的，快过来一起吧 东西多着呢
Well, come on over here. Join me. There's plenty to go around.
这里，好好吃 来点意大利面
Here, enjoy. Have some pasta.
味道很好
It's good.
要不要来点牛排 你喜欢牛排吧？
What about some steak? You want steak?
- 嗯 - 这，来点牛排
- Mmm. - Here, have some steak.
这一大块都是你的
Here's a big piece for you.
给你
There you go.
不错，哈？
Good, huh?
你到底因为什么进来的？
What'd you do to get in here, anyways?
我做了我应该做的事
I did what I had to do.
你搞了个妞还是什么？
So you got a girl or something?
嗯，说来话长
Mmm, it's a long story.
驾驶员，还要多久？
Pilot, how much longer?
预计时间两分钟
Two minutes.
你呢？搞了个妞？
How about you? You have a girl?
- 在家里搞了好几个妞 - 哦，是吗？
- Got a few girls back home. - Oh, yeah?
是的
Yeah.
- 你在这没有男朋友吧？ - 滚蛋吧
- You have a boyfriend in here or no? - Get the fuck out of here.
这是，这是雷诺斯的
This is- it's Reynolds's.
- 看来情况不妙 - 快挖
- Not a good sign, Nick. - Just dig.
- 上帝！ - 雷诺斯
- Jesus Christ! - Reynolds!
- 他失去意识了 - 雷诺斯
- He's unconscious. - Reynolds!
他死了，尼克 他死了
He's gone, Nick. He's gone.
氧气罩？
- Oxygen? - Get something to get him out!
- 找东西把他弄出来
Detective: He's got IV lines going to his-
他把他铐住了
He's got him cuffed!
你有开手铐的钥匙吗？
Nick: Listen, you got your keys to the cuffs?
- 嗯！ - 嗯！
- Mmm! - Mmm.
妈的
Shit.
哦，上帝，吃的真爽
Oh, God, I'm so happy.
你的幸运日，啊？ 有东西吃
Your lucky day, huh? Get some food.
这里，要拍张照吗？
Here, wanna take a shot at this?
- 这是什么？ - 知道怎么用吗？
- What is it? - Know how to use it?
不知道
No.
哦，该死，快看
Inmate: Oh, shit! Check this out!
他疯了
He's crazy!
现在别停下，伙计
Don't stop now, partner!
干掉他，快！ 把他头割下来
Finish him, come on! Take his head off!
割下来
Take it off!
我需要洗个澡，典狱长
I need a shower, Warden.
把他弄出去
Get him out of there!
唐尼根，你的表几点了？
Nick: Dunnigan, what time do you have?
1点37分
37.
到这里我们大约花了15分钟
Took us roughly 15 minutes to get here.
是吗？
Yeah?
雷诺斯的氧气被设定在1点15分关闭
Reynolds's air was rigged to shut off at 1:15.
如果谢尔顿能准时吃到午餐 他应该能活着
If Shelton would have got his lunch on time, he'd still be alive.
去他妈的，尼克
Fuck this guy, Nick.
他想要玩游戏 我们也可以跟他玩
He wants to play games, we can play games too.
我们得把手套摘下来
We need to take the gloves off.
不行
No.
尼克，我是莎拉 听着，克莱德杀了他的牢友
Nick, it's Sarah. Listen, Clyde murdered his cell-mate.
典狱长大发雷霆，要把他移至禁闭室
The warden is furious. He's moving him to solitary.
目前我就只知道这些
That's all I know right now.
目前什么情况？
How are we doing?
不错，你能相信吗？
Great. Can you believe this?
把他iPod拆了找线索
Checking his iPod for clues.
我对我女儿也这么做
I do the same thing with my daughter's.
有收获吗？
Learn anything?
恩，他们都听垃圾音乐
Yeah, they both got shit taste in music.
我们有招术跟这个家伙玩了吗？
We got a game plan with this guy or what?
招术？
Game plan?
我跟你说，我有个招术
I tell you, I got a game plan.
给我跟他五分钟时间 我会搞残这个混蛋
Give me five minutes alone with him and I'll cripple the fucker.
我才不管他家庭发生了什么
I don't give a shit what happened to his family.
没有借口
It's no excuse.
哇
Wow.
就在这
Stop right there.
进屋去
Step into the cell.
我们发现雷诺斯了
We found Reynolds.
当赶到时太迟了
Moments too late, from what I hear.
我必须打给他老婆 告诉她丈夫被活埋了
I had to call his wife and tell her that her husband had been buried alive.
司法制度需要严厉，尼克
Justice should be harsh, Nick,
尤其是对于那种对他人拒绝公正的人
but especially for those who denied it to others.
杀你的牢友呢？怎么回事？
And your cell-mate? What was that about?
你杀死这人就是因为午餐来迟了
You murdered a man because your lunch was late.
不
No.
不，不，是你杀了他 因为你没有信守承诺
No. No, you murdered him because you couldn't keep your word.
我们达成了协议，你和我 下午1点
We made a deal, you and I: 00 PM.
那是一个非常重要的原则 我希望你能开始学会，尼克
That's a pretty important principle I'd like you start learning, Nick:
- 遵守你的诺言 - 哦，真的吗？
- keeping your word. - Oh, really?
当你折磨并杀死那些人时 你又在按什么原则行事
What principle was at work when you tortured and killed those people?
那就是每个人都应该为自己的行为负责
That everyone must be held accountable for their actions.
你以为你的妻子女儿 对你以她们的名义杀人
You think your wife and daughter would feel good
会感觉很好吗？
about you killing in their name?
我妻子和女儿再也没有感觉了
My wife and daughter can't feeI anything.
他们死了
They're dead.
嘿，尼克
Hey, Nick?
查克莱德的不动产一事 史坦菲德法官拒绝了我们
On Clyde's real estate, Judge Stansfield shut us down.
他在寻找某个合法案例 我不知道是否存在
He's looking for some sort of legal precedent that I'm not sure exists.
- 但？ - 但…
- But? - But...
我想我可能找到了其它方法
I think I may have found a way around it.
- 我要找一个朋友帮忙 - 你的朋友是谁？
- I'll call in a favor from a friend. - Who's your friend?
不能透露朋友的名字 不然他们不会帮忙
You don't name your friends or they stop doing you favors.
坎特雷尔还说了什么
Something else Cantrell said.
没有，就这些了 乔纳斯，你好
No, that was all you. Jonas, hi.
她思考的模式和你一样，尼克 我看你把她训练得很不错
She's thinking just like you, Nick. Guess you trained her well.
- 有天她会坐上我的位子 - 我们透透气去吧
- One day she'll have my job. - Let's get some air.
克莱德的政府契约款困扰着我
Clyde's government contract payments were bothering me,
因此我动用了一些旧关系 我们要见个人
so I pulled some ancient strings. We're meeting someone.
会是谁呢？
Who might that be?
那些做真正下流事情的人 所以我们才能够住着美国梦
Someone who does some really nasty shit so we can live the American dream.
那么克莱德终于疯了吗？
So Clyde finally lost it?
一定是有人真的惹毛他了
Somebody must have really pissed him off.
你和谢尔顿一起工作过？对吧？
You worked with Shelton, is that right?
首先，我从没来过这里 我们也从没有对过话
Okay, first of all, I was never here and we never spoke.
告诉我们在对付谁 谢尔顿是间谍还是…
Tell us what we're dealing with. Shelton was a spy or-
间谍太稀松平常了 我就是间谍
Spies are a dime a dozen. I'm a spy.
克莱德是天才 他是会动脑筋那个
Clyde is a brain. He's a think-tank type guy.
他的专长是低速冲击动力操作
His specialty was low-impact kinetic operations.
这是他杀人一种美化的说法吗？
Is this a hell of a fancy way to say that he kills people?
我们杀人
We kill people.
他可以不共处一室就能干出来
He figured out how to do it without ever being in the same room.
这是他的天赋，而且他是最优秀的
It was his gift, and he was the best.
有次我们对付一个狡猾的目标
One time we're tasking this tricky target.
我们用巡航导弹、猛禽战机
I mean, we're using cruise missiles and predators
甚至动用了B2隐形轰炸机 飞到这家伙的别墅去炸他
and we even had a B-2 bomber flatten this guy's villa with a JDAM.
我们循规蹈矩的方法浪费了数百万
All right? We're burning up millions in ordnance
连这家伙的影子都没有见到
and we're getting nowhere with this guy.
所以我们找来了克莱德 请他解决这个问题
So we call Clyde and we ask him to solve our problem.
克莱德发明一项高强力缝线
Clyde develops a Kevlar thread
有着碳纤维制的高科技制轮装置
with a high-tech ratchet made of carbon fiber
能够安装在领带里
put in a necktie.
两天后，坏蛋太太回到家
Two days later, Mrs. Bad Guy comes home,
发现坏蛋先生倒在浴室的瓷砖上
finds Mr. Bad Guy dead on the bathroom tile,
窒息而死
choked to death.
我所说的是，只能假设这家伙可以
What I'm saying is, just assume that this guy can hear and see
听到或看到你的一举一动
everything that you're doing.
不，我们把他关起来了 高度戒备中
Nick: No, we've got him locked away, maximum security.
如果他在监狱，那是因为他想在狱中
Man: If he's in jail, it's because he wants to be in jail.
他是个天生的战略家 他的每个行动都有意义
He's a born tactician. Every move that he makes, it means something.
他杀死牢友，你以为是随意的吗？
That cell-mate that he killed- you think that was random?
不是
No.
那只是棋盘上被摆布的一个棋子
That's a pawn being moved off the board.
换作我，我会找出下一个目标
If I were you, I'd be looking for the next piece.
和那案子有关联的每个人
Anybody who had anything to do with that case,
他不会放过你们的
he's gonna be coming after you.
那你的意思是？ 你是说我们无法阻止他？
So what are you saying? You saying we can't stop him?
走进他的牢房 给他脑袋一颗子弹
Walk into his cell and put a bullet in his head.
除此之外？ 别无他法，你无法阻止他
Aside from that? No, you can't stop him.
如果克莱德想要你死，你就死
If Clyde wants you dead, you're dead.
- 你好 - 莎拉？莎拉，是尼克
- Hello? - Sarah? Sarah, it's Nick.
安排和伯奇法官会个面
Set up a meeting with Judge Burch.
我们得让她帮我们把克莱德监押起来
We need her to help us keep Clyde on ice.
帮我们做什么？尼克 他已经在牢里了
Help us with what, Nick? The man's in prison.
他比我们想象的更可怕
He's worse than we thought.
- 切斯特是你的男朋友，对吧？ - 切斯特
- Chester's your boyfriend, right? - Chester.
是的
Yeah.
很好，也许去他那待几天
Good. Maybe stay a few days at his place.
再叫唐尼派辆巡逻车到我家来
And have Dunnigan send a patroI car to my house.
对此很抱歉，莎拉
Sorry about this, Sarah.
我不能取代刑法
Judge Burch: I can't supersede the penal code.
你们已经把他关入禁闭室
You've already got him in solitary.
到下周随便一个律师助理就会让他出来
A half-decent paralegal will have him out of there by next week.
我们只想限制他的选择
We just want to limit his options;
减少他的联系，减少渠道
give him less contact, less access,
即使只是解除他一个星期的委托权
even if it's just rescinding his mandatory exercise period for a week.
- 用什么名义？ - 什么都可以
- Under what cause? - Whatever cause you want.
随便用什么法条
Wrap it around whatever piece of legal doctrine
只要能合理化这个即可，法官大人
that helps you rationalize it, Your Honor.
那么，我直说吧
So let me get this straight:
你们想要我侵犯上帝赋予他的权利？
you want me to violate his God-given civil rights
以某种罪恶第六感的名义
in the name of some murky sense of the greater good.
先生们，是这个意思吗？
Is that the gist of it, gentlemen?
好吧，我入伙
Okay. I'm game.
只是别想持续太久，好吗？
Just don't plan on it sticking for long, all right?
等会，你要接电话？
Wait, you're gonna take that,
你训斥过我接电话的事情
after all the grief you've given me over cell phones?
那是当法官的好处之一，瑞斯先生
That's one of the benefits of being a judge, Mr. Rice.
我相当可以随心所欲
I can pretty much do whatever I want.
喂？
Hello?
哦，上帝
Oh my God.
退后，退后
Nick: Back out. Back out.
…在市政厅，尽管还无法证实这些细节
Female reporter:... at city hall, though we are unable to confirm the details,
但我们知道至少一人死亡
we do know that at least one person is dead
官方称很可能是谋杀
in what officials are calling a possible murder.
我们会有记者继续…
We have reporters on the ground...
上来
Up.
有人在帮这家伙
Somebody's helping this guy-
手机里的炸弹 而她毫不知情
a bomb in that phone, and she doesn't know about it.
谁能做到呢？
Who had access?
你还好吗？
Are you okay?
我是战争里过来的，还有两个前妻 我没事的
I've survived the war and two ex-wives. I'll be fine.
你还好吗？
How are you holding up?
我还好
I'm good.
现在你把法官也杀了？
So you're killing judges now?
以我的经验来看，尼克 只有血的教训才能持久
In my experience, Nick, lessons not learned in blood are soon forgotten.
复仇能让你在晚上得到温暖吗
And vengeance keeps you warm at night.
复仇？
Vengeance?
这就是你所认为的吗？复仇？
That's what you think this is about? Vengeance?
还会是什么呢？
What else could it be?
不，尼克，我有10年的时间可以复仇 如果我要做的话
No, Nick, I had 10 years for vengeance, if that's what I wanted.
你没意识到我每天早上八点看你上班？
You don't think that I watch you go to work every morning at 8:00 AM?
或者看着凯莉带丹尼斯8点15去上学？
Or that I watch Kelly take Denise to schooI, 8:15?
不，我可以在任何时候毁了你和你的家庭
No, I could have slaughtered you or your family anytime I wanted!
你甚至想过碰我的家人…
You even think about touching my family-
you even think about touching my family...
我是做我的工作
I do my job.
我是做的最出色的
I'm the best at it.
- 做的不错 - 你在做你的工作？
- It works. - You were doing yourjob
以对你有利的方式，尼克 对你有利的方式
the way that best served you, Nick- the way that best served you.
- 这点得改变了 - 你想怎样，克莱德？
- That has to change. - What do you want, Clyde?
你在和整个世界作战？ 这不会令任何人退却
You at war with the whole world? It's not gonna bring anybody back.
不，我在和这个…
No, I'm at war with this-
这个…这个破烂的玩意作战
this- this broken thing-
把你和我连在一起的玩意
this thing that brought you and I together.
这烂玩意对神经正常的人有用
This broken thing works for people that are sane.
你以为你在做的事情能够改变任何事情吗？
You think doing what you're doing is gonna change anything?
你和其它帮助你的人
You and whoever else you have helping you
都要付出代价
are gonna pay.
我认为你并不知道谁在帮我 或我在做什么？
I don't think you have any idea who's helping me or what I'm doing.
迟早的事
It's a matter of time.
看，你看过尸体 你见到烟雾
See, you see the bodies, you see the smoke,
可还有更大的场面等着你
but the larger picture still eludes you.
说说看
Do tell.
我很想说…
I would like to...
但我选择演给你看
but I would rather show you.
我仍然对你有信念 所以我会给你最后一次机会
I still have faith in you, so I'm gonna give you one last chance.
这交易是
Here's the deal:
释放我，并在早上六点前撤销所有的指控
release me and drop all charges by 6:00 AM.
- 早上六点，尼克 - 不然怎样？
- 6:00 AM, Nick. - Or what?
不然我杀了每个人
Or I kill everyone.
- 你好？ - 莎拉
- Hello? - Nick: Yeah, Sarah,
他一定有同伙 可能就是牢里的某个人
he has to have an accomplice- probably somebody inside the prison.
我们必须调查所有犯人的档案 看能否找出某种关联
We have to go through all the prisoners' files to find some sort of connection.
档案要送到办公室吗？
Do you want the files brought to the office?
不，没时间了 叫大家一起到监狱来
No, there isn't time. Get everybody together and bring them to the prison.
我们要进驻
We're moving in.
别再看表了
Stop looking at your watch.
你朋友那边有消息吗？
Anything from your friend?
与巴拿马那边的条款很棘手
This treaty with Panama is a mess.
我们无法得到任何有关财产持有的记录
We can't access anything about specific property holdings,
不过我朋友发现了一个后门
but my friend found this tiny loophole
可以浏览克莱德公司开销记录
that grants us access to Clyde's corporate expenses.
有用么？
Does that help?
那么对比下费城出售过的工业资产价格
So we match sale prices of industrial properties sold in Philly
和他公司所购买过的物品金额
up against purchases made by his corporation.
我知道了
Okay, I got it.
- 嘿，尼克，我能问你点事吗？ - 嗯？
- Hey, Nick, can I ask you something? - Hmm?
你现在会做同样的选择吗？
Would you do it the same way now?
你仍会帮多比达成协议吗？
Would you still cut a deal for Darby?
这是工作呀，莎拉 我们得做出选择
This is the job, Sarah. We have to make choices.
- 但你做出正确选择了吗？ - 我们的选择正确，对吧？
- But did you make the right choice? - We made the right choice, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
我35岁了，尼克
I'm 35, Nick.
有许多东西…许多的可能性
And there are things- there are possibilities
是我现在无法拥有的
that I'm not gonna have now.
没关系，我知道这是交易的一部分
And it's okay. I know it's part of the deal.
别误会我 我喜欢为你工作
And don't get me wrong. I love working for you.
但我只想弄清楚我放弃的那些东西
But I just want to make sure I gave up those things
不光是为了高定罪率
for more than just a high conviction rate.
你要喝咖啡吗？
Do you want any more coffee?
不
No.
好了
All right.
好了，我们集中精神 这人不是神仙
All right, let's just get focused here. This guy's not God.
他不是万能的 他只是准备充分而已
He's not the All Powerful. He's just well-prepared.
我们也需要准备充分
We need to be equally well-prepared.
回家休息一两个小时 然后回来重新开始
Take a couple of hours, go home, come back. We'll get a fresh start.
好吗？
Okay?
过来，老人家 看我们能否给你买到早餐
Man: Come on, old man, let's see if we can find you some breakfast.
嘿，尼克，去休息一会吧
Hey, Nick, get some rest.
待我问候切斯特 我几时才能见到他？
Give Chester my regards. When do I get to meet him?
哦，还不到那个时候
Oh, he's not ready for that.
晚安，琼纳斯
'Night, Jonas.
我不知道这个案子的结果会怎样，尼克
I don't know how this one's gonna turn out, Nick.
我们得阻止他 那就是结果
We're gonna stop him. That's how it's gonna turn out.
啊！
Ahh!
莎拉
Sarah.
在过去的48个小时中 6名司法部的官员
Reporter: In the past 48 hours, six officials from the Justice Department
死于一连串的有预谋的袭击中
have been killed in a series of vicious and premeditated attacks.
这还是美国历史上的第一次
This marks the first time in the history of the United States
很显然政府官员在被系统性地谋杀
where government officials have been, by all appearances,systematically murdered.
我们会继续跟进事件的发展 为你带来最新最细的报道…
We'll continue to follow this story and bring you up-to-the-minute details...
尼克，很抱歉我现在不得不这样做 但我们在这里找到了些东西
Nick, I'm sorry to have to do this now, but we've got something here.
就在墙外发现了这个…
Found this right outside the wall-
无线电装置
radio beacon-
当人通过大门时 发送信号给车上的炸弹
sent an arming signal to the car bombs when they went through the gate.
警卫说他们抵达这前 检查过每一辆车
Dunnigan: Security said they checked every car before anybody got in them.
他们没有检查油箱 大概那些奸鸟会放那里
They didn't check the gas tanks. That's where the clever prick put 'em.
也是个精密的玩意
Real precise stuff too.
如果他想，可以干掉更多的人
Could have taken out a lot more if he wanted to.
- 尼克的车呢？ - 怪就怪在这里
- Cantrell: What about Nick's car? - That's the weird thing.
他的车子没问题 没被做过手脚
It's clean- hadn't been touched.
我得走了
I gotta go.
天呀
Woman: Jesus Christ.
请回避下
Privacy, please.
那让我直说吧
So let me get this straight:
我们不光知道谁干的
not only do we know who did it,
而且我们把他关起来了 可是他仍旧在杀人？
we have him locked up and he's still killing people?
你们这些人一定把这案子搞砸了
You boys sure fucked this one up.
媒体会弄死我们的
The press is gonna kill us.
有人能给我解释一下吗？
Can someone explain this to me?
暂时不能
We can't yet.
你怎么还像安然无事一样，乔纳斯
How did this get away from you, Jonas?
说来复杂，埃普丽尔
It's complicated, April.
他非常狡猾 他非常愤怒
He's very smart. He's very angry.
我们估计有同伙在外面帮助他
We assume he has an accomplice helping him on the outside.
我不要这种谈话
I'm not having this conversation.
我不关心他有多聪明 或者是谁在帮他
I don't care how smart he is or who's helping him.
我们将发布声明说我们抓到了嫌犯 我们正在追查线索…
We'll release a statement saying we have suspects, we're following leads-
- 无需惊慌 - 市长，我向你保证
- nothing alarming. - Mayor, you have my word,
我们会阻止这家伙的 他不会再伤害任何人
we are gonna stop this guy. He's not gonna hurt anybody else.
现在开始我给你们每个人加强保安
I'm assigning security to each of you from now on.
控制住局势，先生们
Get this situation under control, gentlemen.
爸爸？
Dad?
我打赌你不记得我做的那个
I bet you don't remember when I did that.
我打赌我记得
I bet you I do.
怎么了？
What?
没什么
Nothing.
你和你妈妈要度几天假
You and your mother are going away on a little vacation, that's all.
- 你喜欢假期，对吧？ - 是啊
- You like vacations, right? - Yeah.
好
Good.
可为什么？
But why?
为什么不现在去？
Why not now?
好的
Okay.
不需要理由，对吧？
Don't need an excuse, right?
好吧
All right.
别用电话，别用信用卡，别用电脑 只能用现金
No phone calls, no credit cards, no computers- just cash.
爸爸，你来吗？
Daddy, are you coming?
哦，是的，当然
Oh, yeah, of course.
- 当然我会过去 - 最好这样，尼克
- Of course I am. - You'd better, Nick.
是你一年级的时候吧？
It was first grade, hmm?
你妈妈帮你拼的
Your mother helped you with the spelling.
是我的生日
It was my birthday.
- 我们得走了！ - 我们走
- Man: We need to go! - Let's go.
- 再见，爸爸 - 再见
- Bye, Daddy. - Bye.
- 我爱你，爸爸 - 我也爱你
- Love you, Daddy. - Love you too.
- 尼克，你的电话线没有问题 - 很好
- Nick, your phone lines are clear. - Good.
电话线正常，没被动过手脚 没什么问题
No bugs; nothing's been tampered with. You're good.
你本该接受我的条件的
You should have taken my deal.
他妈的六个无辜的人 那就是你要玩的吗？啊？
That's six fucking innocent people. Is that how you want to play it? Huh?
没事，没事 尼克，我知道你很生气
It's okay. It's okay, Nick. I know you're angry.
那很好，就是要那样 应该是那样
That's good. That's what it takes. That's how it has to be.
如果我说你过去是对的 我过去是错了呢？
What if I said you was right and I was wrong?
如果我说，好吧，我们来审判他们吧？
What if I had said, "Well, let's take them to trial"? Huh?
我会说你进步了
Then I would say you're making progress.
那我们就会败诉 阿米和多比都会双双自由
And we might have lost! And Ames and Darby would both go free.
你还不懂吗？
Don't you get that?
靠
Fuck.
你不在乎，尼克 你连试都没试
You didn't care, Nick. You didn't even try.
你本可以昂首阔步走出法庭的
You could have walked out of that courtroom with your head held high.
我本可以接受那点的，尼克
I could have lived with that, Nick.
我会继续昂首阔步
I keep my head up.
而你将就此终结
And you will end this.
我才刚刚热身
I'm just getting warmed up.
这就是该死的冯・克劳塞维茨战争论
This is Von Clausewitz shit- total fucking war.
你该死
You fuck.
不
No.
我要把这一切推翻
I'm gonna pull the whole thing down.
我要他妈把这瘟疫般、枯烂的庙宇
I'm gonna bring the whole fucking diseased, corrupt temple
扣在你脑袋上
down on your head.
会是惊涛骇浪的
It's gonna be Biblical.
老天，尼克，她是个好孩子
Cantrell: Jesus, Nick, she was a good kid.
是我们把这一切揽上身的吗？
Did we bring this all on ourselves?
绝对不是
Absolutely not.
你其实也不太确定，是吗？
You don't actually believe that, do you?
先生们，抱歉 我们得走了
Gentlemen? Sorry, but we need to get going
如果还去参加记者会的话
if we're going to make it to the press conference.
走前我想给你读一段我以前的演讲
I want to read you something from my speech before we go.
我们必须不畏恐惧
"We must not give in to the fear.
我们必须面对那些我们最恐惧的
We must face those things we fear the most.
我们必须恳求我们更好的天使
We must appeaI to our better angels. "
说太多了？
Too much?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
以前你问我是不是我们给自己带来的这些
It's just before, when you asked if we brought this on ourselves-
其实不是我们
we didn't.
是我自己
I did.
当我年轻的时候，我确实想改变体制
When I was young, I really wanted to change the system.
你知道我准备斗争 我准备做最好的不计后果
You know, I was ready to fight. I was gonna be the best no matter what.
你那里让一步 你这里让一步
You give an inch here, you give an inch there,
你逐渐也进了游戏
you get caught up in the game.
然后你发现你试图想改变的体制…
And then you realize that the system that you're trying to change-
却改变了你
it changed you.
乔纳斯，我有些迷失方向了
Jonas, I've lost my way somewhere.
看，记得我告诉过你的
Look, remember what I told you?
最难的部分不是做决定
The hard part isn't making the decision.
而是承受它
It's living with it.
所有人保持警觉
Man: Everybody stay sharp.
我们要上路了
We're on the move.
- 没事吧？ - 车子挂了
- We all right? - Dunnigan: It's dead.
电子系统挂了
Electrical system's fried.
那边是怎么回事？
Man over radio: What's going on back there?
唐尼根，叫他们带乔纳斯离开
Dunnigan, tell them to get Jonas away from here.
那他妈是什么东西？
What the fuck is that?
趴下，趴下
Get down, get down!
乔纳斯！乔纳斯！
Jonas! Jonas!
- 乔纳斯！乔纳斯！ - 不，尼克，蹲下
- Jonas! Jonas! - No, Nick! Get back!
乔纳斯，放开你的手
Nick: Jonas! Get your hands off me!
乔纳斯，离开车子 乔纳斯！
Jonas! Get out of the car! Jonas!
离开车子，放开你的手
Get out of the car! Get off of me!
请听我说
Dunnigan: Please listen to me!
乔纳斯
Jonas!
Jonas.
我叫你处理好这事的
I told you to handle this.
你没做到
You didn't.
现在我们有个坐牢的疯子
Now we have a jailed psychopath
计划让整座城市臣服于他的脚下
that's managed to bring this entire city to its knees.
我的一个朋友刚刚被杀害
One of my friends was just murdered.
我不止一个朋友走了，市长
More than one of my friends is gone, Mayor.
我该做的事情是炒了你
What I should do is fire you.
嗯？现在
Hmm? Right now.
我辞职
I resign.
- 那是你真正的回答么 - 我想那样最好
- Is that your real answer? - I think that's best.
不行
No.
我不允许你辞职 把圣经拿给我
I'm not gonna allow that to happen. Bring me the Bible.
我不会让罪犯决定费城该不该有地方检察官
I'm not gonna let some criminal decide whether Philadelphia has a DA or not.
现在，你是代理地方检察官
As of now, you're acting District Attorney.
我们稍后会有个正式的宣誓
We'll have a formal swearing in later.
目前这就足够了 起立！
For now this will suffice. Stand up.
把你的左手放在圣经上 举起你的右手
Put your left hand on the Bible. Raise your right hand.
跟我复读
Repeat after me.
- 我，尼古拉斯・瑞斯 - 我，尼古拉斯・瑞斯
- I, Nicolas Rice... - I, Nicolas Rice...
- 庄严地发誓… - 庄严地发誓…
- ... do solemnly swear... - ... do solemnly swear...
- 我将支持… - 我将支持…
- ... that I will support... - ... that I will support...
- 服从… - 服从…
- ... obey... - ... obey...
并捍卫美利坚联邦宪法…
...and defend the Constitution of the United States...
以及宾夕法尼亚州法律…
...and the Constitution of the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania...
民众不上班，小孩不上学
People aren't going to work; kids aren't going to schooI.
他们很害怕 我不能怪他们
They're scared, and I don't blame them.
所以我要动用费城法典的紧急条款
So I'm implementing the emergency provision of the Philadelphia code.
我们将本市戒严
We're gonna lock this city down.
现在开始，谁都不能在本市自由行动
Starting now, no one moves in this city unrestricted.
我要展示勇气给大家看
I want a show of force for the public-
制服警员，警探 12小时轮班
uniforms, detectives, 12-hour shifts.
每个角落安置武装警察
Put an armed cop on every corner.
如果有必要给停车收费员霰弹枪 那就给
If you have to give shotguns to the meter maids, do it.
民众就不会怀疑
There should be no doubt in people's minds
这个城市是安全的 在我们的掌握之中
that this city is secure and under our control.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，克莱德 我明白了
Okay, Clyde. I get it.
听着，杀死坎特雷尔的装置
Dunnigan: Listen, that contraption that killed Cantrell,
是一种武装后的拆弹机器人
it was a weaponized bomb-disposal robot.
你能相信么？
Can you believe that?
那该死的东西有影像，夜视镜… 说出来的都有
Damn thing had video, night vision- you name it.
就像军事应用接口，我的老天
It's like military APl, for Christ's sakes.
那是反坦克的，尼克
That's anti-tank rounds, Nick.
我想他会把你留作压轴
I think he's saving you for last.
尼克，我是认真的
Nick, I'm serious.
我感激你的洞察力
I appreciate the insight.
尼克，你得赶在他前面 如果你想活命
Nick, you gotta get in front of this guy if you want to stay alive.
我可能有办法了…
I may have a way-
一个朋友的东西会帮我解决
something a friend is helping me out with.
你朋友是谁？
Who's your friend?
一个叫切斯特的朋友 我会给你回电话
A friend named Chester. I'll call you back.
谢谢，莎拉
Thank you, Sarah.
我是尼克，给我最近10年这里卖掉的
This is Nick. Give me the real-estate listing
每一笔工业地产的清单
of every industrial property sold here in the last 10 years.
混蛋东西
Motherfucker.
你在开玩笑，是吧？
You're kidding me, right?
你是说这个地方是克莱德的
You're saying Clyde owns this place?
事情很明显，对吧？
Something about it sticks out, right?
嗯
Yeah.
我认为你要做一件事，是我想的那样吗？
What- are you gonna do what I think you're gonna do?
- 他的公民权怎么办？ - 去他妈的公民权
- What about his civil rights? - Fuck his civiI rights.
哈哈，不错
Yes!
这里面一定有问题
There's got to be something in here.
嗯
Dunnigan: Yeah.
记得这个在屋子外吗？
Remember this from outside the house?
恩
Yeah.
打开那个
Get that right there.
真他妈难以置信
Dunnigan: Un-fucking-believable.
看吧
Look at this.
当心脚下
Nick: Watch your step.
这家伙挖隧道到监狱？
This guy tunneled into prison?
哦，该死
Nick: Oh, shit.
靠…橡胶炸弹
Dunnigan: Fuck- Semtex.
警察制服，其它的伪装品
Got police uniforms, other disguises.
他挖通了每个牢房
Nick: He tunneled into every cell.
这边
Over here.
他故意要转到禁闭室
He wanted to be transferred to solitary.
给你个惊喜，王八蛋
Surprise, motherfucker.
- 他不在这里 - 如果他不在那，那会在哪？
- He's not here! - If he's not there, then where is he?
诺莫斯，你眼睛怎么了？
Nomos, what happened to your eye?
哦，说来话长
Oh, long story.
站住，先生
Stop right there, sir.
请你让我看看证件
Let me see your ID, please.
- 好的，当然 - 谢谢
- Yeah, sure. - Thank you.
转身，先生 手臂伸开
Turn around, sir. Extend your arms.
今晚有活动吗？
Something going on tonight?
- 市长 - 嗯，市长
- The mayor. - Mmm, mayor.
看看这个
Look at this.
他偷偷接通了监狱摄像机
He tapped into the prison cameras.
老天，到处都是摄像机
Jesus, he's got cameras everywhere.
- 该死 - 那是你家吗？
- Shit. - Is that your house?
是的
Yes.
宝贝，告诉我你们没事
Baby, please tell me you're okay.
丹尼斯，她在哪？
Denise- where is she?
她跟你在一起？ 你确定？
Is she with you? Are you sure?
好
Okay.
待着别动 我一会再解释
Stay where you are. I'll explain later.
我爱你
I love you.
（取得胜利就要重兵集结在 所有权力活动中心--敌人的重心）
冯・克劳塞维茨
Nick: Von Clausewitz.
看看那个
Look at that.
他在市政厅
He's at City Hall.
你可以走了，先生
You're free to go, sir.
- 抱歉造成不便，先生 - 不用，没关系
- Sorry for the inconvenience, sir. - No, don't worry about it.
安全要比抱歉重要，是吧？
Better to be safe than sorry, right?
准备疏散大楼
Dunnigan: Get ready to evacuate the building.
我们需要一支战术小队和防爆小组
We'll need a tactical unit and a bomb squad.
坏主意，叫他们悄悄进去
Bad idea. Have them come in soft.
如果谢尔顿认出我或我们中任何一个人 事情就糟糕了
If Shelton spots them or any of us, we're fucked.
嘿
Hey.
- 战术小队在哪？ - 正赶来
- Where's the tactical team? - En route.
- 他们悄悄地过来，不鸣警笛 - 拆弹部队呢？
- They're coming in soft- no sirens. - Bomb squad?
你正在看着呢
You're looking at it.
对，那我们走北边楼梯 你走西边
Right, okay. We take the north surge; you take the west.
我们再联系
We'll call.
- 喔，喔，喔 - 请出示证件
- Whoa whoa whoa whoa. - IDs, please.
- 他是地区检察官 - 很不错，麻烦出示证件
- He's the fucking DA. - Good for him. IDs, please.
今晚这里怎么回事
What's going on here tonight?
- 所有高层在这开安保会议 - 哪一层？
- Security meeting with all the brass. - What floor?
六楼…会议室
6th floor- caucus room.
- 这是几楼？ - 那是五楼，先生
- What floor is this? - That's the 5th floor, sir.
正好是高层会议室的下面
Directly below the caucus room.
如果我们发现混蛋正在作案 我们要抓活的
You catch this motherfucker red-handed, we gotta take him alive.
他在哪？
Where is he?
我们到底在找什么？
What the fuck are we looking for?
等等，等等
Wait wait wait.
在那
Right there.
退后，别碰任何东西
Garza: Stand back. Don't touch anything.
那绝对不是我的第一感觉
It wasn't exactly my first instinct.
麻烦给我看看证件
Can I see your ID, please?
好了，下一辆，往前走
All right, next car, pull forward!
爆炸物
Garza: Malglinite.
那是凝固汽油弹 这鬼东西基本上会炸跨整层楼
That's napalm, basically. This shit'll take out the entire floor
和这层上方的楼层
and the one above us.
看起来…好像是由这支手机所触发
Looks like it's- looks like it's triggered by this cell phone here.
什么？一来电话就激活了？
What? So an incoming call arms it?
是的，也许30秒就爆炸了
Yeah. Maybe 30 seconds till boom time.
- 天呀 - 唐尼根，你在干嘛
- Jesus. - Dunnigan, what are you doing?
- 我要打给市长的保安人员 - 不行
- I'm calling the mayor's security. - We can't.
克莱德在盯着 如果他看见他们疏散，他会引爆的
Clyde is watching. He sees him evacuate and he will detonate this thing.
我们不能向市长透露
We don't tell the mayor anything.
那我们该怎么做？
So what do we do?
等一下
Man: Wait a second.
来了
We've got something.
他要停下了
Man over radio: He's pulling up.
市长埃普丽尔・亨利
Man: Mayor April Henry.
感谢各位的匆忙赶来
Thank you for coming in on short notice.
我有一个简单的问题
Mayor: I have one simple question.
为什么克莱德・谢尔顿还在我的城市？
Why is Clyde Shelton still in my city?
我现在拒绝相信
Now I refuse to believe
这个人比国土安全部
that one man is smarter than Homeland Security,
FBI，行政司法长官或费城警察还聪明
the FBl, the sheriff's department, or Philly PD.
我不管我们怎么做
I don't care how we do it, or what kind
或者必须启动哪种的晦涩的司法程序
of obscure legaI justification we have to invoke, gentlemen.
先生们，我不在乎我们要遵守哪条法律
I don't care what laws we have to bend.
但我相信国土安全法案会有一个条款
I am sure that there is a provision of the Homeland Security Act
是我们可以启动的
that we can activate.
明天之前将他赶出这里
Just get him out of here by tomorrow.
克莱德？
Nick: Clyde?
尼克
Nick.
我没料到还会有人陪我
I wasn't expecting company.
嗯，早知道就先稍微打扫一下
Yeah, I would have- I would have cleaned up a little.
从未见过任何人挖隧道到监狱
Never seen anybody tunnel into prison before.
被关进禁闭室的法子很聪明
And the solitary confinement? That was clever.
嗯，那正是赢家的玩法
Well, that's how winners play.
我们要让其他人信服 他做的每一步都是正确的
We convince the other guy he's making all the right moves.
那你抓住我同伙了吗？
So did you ever catch my accomplice?
是的，当然
Yeah, I did.
现在是你的末路了
It's the end of the road for you now.
你玩弄了我们，克莱德 你真的耍得我们团团转
You played us, Clyde. You played us real good.
谢谢
Thank you.
知道么，很高兴你终于能够赏识
You know, I'm glad you finally get to appreciate
我所做的这一切努力了
some of the effort that I put into all of this.
你特别想强调某点，克莱德
Well, you set out to make a point, Clyde.
你做到了
You made it.
不，人们仍然不懂
No, people still don't get it.
他们不重视我试图说的 尼克，不过很快地他们就会了
They don't appreciate what I'm trying to say, Nick, but they will soon enough.
我关心过的一个人曾告诉过我
A man I cared about once told me
我们不能撤回我们已做了的决定
that we can't retract the decisions that we've made,
我们只能影响今后我们要做的决定
we can only affect the decisions we're going to make from here.
- 现在你想拯救我吗，尼克？ - 我在给你一条出路
- Are you trying to save me now, Nick? - I'm giving you a way out.
差别很大
Big difference.
站在你一直在宣扬的那些立场上
Stand up for those principles you've been preaching.
所以你看我们都要负责 克莱德，包括你在内
See, we're all held accountable, Clyde. That includes you.
为何不做正确的事呢？
Why don't we do the right thing here?
我是在做正确的事，尼克
I'm doing the right thing, Nick.
你只需以那种方式去看
You just have to see it that way.
靠着谋杀那些人
By murdering all those people,
你的所作所为只会摧毁你对女儿的记忆
all you're doing is destroying the memory of your daughter
也会对很多人造成你正遭受的痛苦
and causing the same pain that you're suffering from.
那么你有何建议呢，尼克？ 再做另一次交易吗？
So what do you suggest, Nick? Make another deaI?
提最后一次条件？ 是那样子吗？
One finaI offer? Is that what it is?
我不再与杀人凶手做交易了，克莱德
I don't make deals with murderers anymore, Clyde.
你教我的
You taught me that.
终于
Finally.
干得好，好极了
Well done. Bravo.
也许我并非是个很糟的老师
Maybe I wasn't such a bad teacher after all.
如果你干这事，克莱德 这个决定
If you go through with this, Clyde, it's a decision
你后半辈子都要承受这个决定
you'll have to live with for the rest of your life.
对不起，尼克
I'm sorry, Nick.
我也是
Me too.
如我说过的，克莱德
Like I said, Clyde,
你后半辈子都要承受这个决定
it's a decision you'll have to live with for the rest of your life,
我想现在大概还剩25秒钟吧？
which I figure by now is about 25 more seconds.
谢谢观赏
“未曾见一夜”
# Ain't seen a night #
“云开月明”
# Things work out right #
“消逝”
# Go by #
“心中成大事”
# Things on my mind #
“然时不我待”
# And I just don't have the time #
“似物是人非”
# And it don't seem right #
“未见有时”
# Ain't seen a day #
“斯人已无言”
# That I don't hear people say #
“自知人之将去”
# They know they're gonna die #
《守法公民》 “此事已成疯癫”
# This may seem a little bit crazy #
“然斯人亦当勤勉”
# But I don't think you should be so lazy #
“似曾相识处”
# If you think you've heard this before #
“饮酒至阑珊”
# Well, stick around #
“尽其详”
# I'm gonna tell you more #
“吾等皆草民”
# One just like the other #
“恶善伴行生”
# Sin's a good man's brother #
“知否？”
# But is that right? #
“汝知此不可为”
# You tell me that I don't #
“吾遂不为”
# Then I say I won't #
“然尚可为”
# But then I might #
“此行或可众人期”
# You said this is the way it's supposed to be #
“却吾念甚笃”
# But it just don't seem right to me #
“且视而不见”
# And that's outta sight #
“民教重于天”
# Some folks need an education #
“弃之国将不国”
# Don't give up or we'll lose the nation #
“天下之变”
# You say we need a revolution? #
“仿若”
# It seems to be #
“唯此一解矣”
# The only solution. #